What kind of garbage crypto bora is
this?
>> These conditions are conditions we've
seen in the past.
>> This is a bare market.
>> It's never too late to start doing the
right thing. Altcoins are not a
long-term investment. By the time you
see the headline, you you can't really
profit from it because crypto is a
little further out on the risk curve
than stocks. So, it tends to if you
really want closure on that and want to
feel a little bit more confident about
it, normally what you see is you see
these weekly closes below the 50we
moving average.
>> [music]
>> That is is where we're currently
battling right now. A lot of people
assume that just because QE returns that
you're going to have like this massive
move in the market. Remember last cycle
when QE started, Bitcoin actually went
down first and then it went up. What it
shows you is is just when is it a good
time to buy, when is it a good time to
sell? And anytime even if you knew for a
fact bubbles can last for years before
they fully align. We have not had an all
season cycle. I don't care what anyone
says.
Go wild.
She's [music] the queen of the game.
Stacking crypto like it's her claim to
fame. If you want success, then take a
look away. [music]
Our guest today is Ben Cohen. He is the
founder of Into the Cryptoverse. He is
not only the superstar market analyst,
he's also a scientist with a PhD in
nuclear engineering and even worked at
NASA. And what makes Ben so different
and so popular is how he uses
engineering logic and math to break down
market cycles. And his approach has
helped hundreds of thousands of
investors make smarter timing decisions
and avoid the kind of emotional trades
that usually cost people a lot of money.
It's so great to have you back. Hello,
Ben.
>> Yeah, it's great to be here. Um, feel
like it's been a while since I've been
on on here, but uh, it was a great talk
the last time last time I was here.
>> Last time we actually met about a year
ago. It was at the Michael Sailor 100K
party and it's been a year, right?
>> Uh, it was the 100K party. We're back at
100K levels.
>> Yeah. And for reference, gold has been
up what over 50% and Nvidia
uh as well 36% I think. What kind of
garbage crypto boring is this?
>> Yeah, I don't imagine there's a 100k
party this year. [laughter]
Uh yeah. No, I mean it's it I I mean I
really it's it's kind of like what we've
seen in in some prior cycles with
crypto. I think you could argue that
crypto is a little further out on the
risk curve than, you know, than stocks
and and so it tends to underperform
first. Saw very similar similar type of
stuff back in 2019 where stocks were
continuing to do well as quantitative
tightening came to an end and as
interest rates were cut. Uh but crypto
started to stall out a little bit
sooner. So you could argue because
crypto is a little further out on the
risk curve, it's a little bit more
sensitive to, you know, to liquidity
conditions and that sort of stuff uh
than, you know, than than things in the
S&P. And then gold, of course, has been
doing phenomenally well, but these macro
conditions for years have been very
favorable for metals. And my guess is
that metals will continue to do well
probably until the end of the decade
would be my guess.
>> And what about Bitcoin? Because we call
it a digital gold. Well, what happened
to Bitcoin?
>> Yeah. So I like I I don't really view
Bitcoin as a riskoff asset. I mean so
gold is a riskoff asset. It does really
well, you know, under under certain
types of macro conditions and and when
you do get sell offs like the one we got
in April, gold is is really quick to get
back to all-time highs and then of
course stocks take a little bit longer.
Uh let me share my screen here. Um
and we can talk a little bit more about
it. So, if you look at Bitcoin, you
know, Bitcoin is really stalled out and
and really what you want to look at in
this case is if you look at Bitcoin
divided by the S&P 500, what you'll
notice is that it it's actually near
where it was back in March, right? Like
it it hasn't really moved a whole lot
since the March lows when valued against
the S&P 500. But again, this type of
weakness that we're witnessing by
Bitcoin is the same type of weakness we
witnessed last cycle as quantitative
tightening sort of wrapped up. Right?
So, we've this purple line shows the
balance sheet of the Federal Reserve.
And you can see that as the balance
sheet started to, you know, start, you
know, as it as it went as we went from
quantitative tightening to quantitative
easing, Bitcoin actually kind of sold
off into that and then it it sort of
came out of it once QE really came back,
right? Once rates really went a lot
lower and when the money printers really
turned on. So, you could argue that the
Bitcoin is kind of in that same phase
right now that it was back in 2019,
although it is a little bit stronger now
than it was in 2019, right? like in 2019
it was struggling a lot more. Um, and by
by this point I I think it was down a
lot more from the from that local high
than it is right now. But regardless,
these conditions are conditions we've
seen in the past like for for Bitcoin.
Um, and I I think one of the things that
makes this cycle so difficult is because
a lot of people want to make it make
this cycle comparable to kind of the end
of prior posth having years like you
know the end of 2021,
uh, the end of 2017 and the end of 2013
when we had euphoria, right? Absolute
euphoria. We had these like massive alt
seasons and whatnot. But the reason why
this peak that we're forming probably in
the fourth quarter of this year, just
like always, the reason why this one
feels a little bit different so far is
because we haven't had that euphoria
phase. And you could argue we haven't
had that euphoria phase because of
monetary policy. And if you actually
look at at retail interest in crypto, if
you like look at the price of Bitcoin
colorcoded by social interest, it's blue
right now, which means really low
interest, right? So this this peak that
we're in right now to me again looks a
lot more like that 2019 move where we
also more or less topped on apathy
rather than topping on euphoria. Um so
that's kind of what I think is happening
right now and and why I think Bitcoin is
behaving in a very different way than a
lot of people uh might have expected for
this time in the cycle.
I think in your recent um video you said
if Bitcoin closes below 50WE um MA twice
then the cycle is usually over. And also
Bloomberg came out with this report that
says uh the cryptobear market wipes out
almost the entire 2025 value increase
that says uh because the crypto market
has dropped about 20% since October 6.
Uh this isn't just a correction. This is
a bare market. What do you think?
>> I don't I mean it look it certainly
could turn into a bare market that I
don't think we can definitively say that
just yet. If you look at the ROI from
the low for Bitcoin and compare it to
the last couple of cycles and you look
at where that peak occurred in October,
it kind of looks like like that could be
the end of the bull market. like it it's
like if if in a year from now if it's
the end of the bull if it turns out it
was the end of the bull market it would
have just been the same as the prior two
cycles right it would have topped after
around the same number of days right so
this top was around uh you know two
cycles ago the top was around day 167
last cycle was 1,059 and you know I
think this one so far was around 1,062
so it it's certainly possible that we're
in a bare market but I would say that if
you really want closure on that and want
to feel a little bit more confident
about it, normally what you see is you
see these weekly closes below the 50week
moving average. Um, and that is is
really what kind of solidifies when the
bull market is is here, right? So, you
can see there in 20 uh 14 and then again
in the next cycle and then again in the
next cycle. So, that is is where we're
currently battling right now. And that's
kind of like, you know, I think it's
more so let's just be a student of the
market and say, "All right, if the cycle
is over, then we're going to start
getting weekly closes below the 50week
moving average and then it's going to
likely set up the 2026 bare market,
right? We'll just view this as a topping
process. But we've we've had a couple of
weekly closes that came close to being
below the 50we moving average and then
Bitcoin was still able to come out of
it." Um,
>> and so I think like, you know, I think
in in the short term, the main times
where Bitcoin kind of found support
around the 50week moving average and
rallied out of it, it was actually when
the 50-day moving average crossed below
the 200 day, right? So if you look at
when it happened in 2024, when you look
at it when it happened in 2025, and even
when it happened in 2023,
all these prior death crosses by Bitcoin
actually corresponded to local lows in
the Bitcoin price. And that's where we
kind of found support at the 50we and
then we rallied into another all-time
high. And so if you look today, you can
see that we're kind of on that same
trajectory right now where we've had,
you know, a series of of lower lows, but
we haven't had the death cross yet. Now,
the death cross should occur around
November, I would say maybe between
November 10th to November 13th or 14th.
I don't know exactly. Uh but sometime
within a week or so, at least from when
we're recording this video. Um and so
that's going to be the signal for me, I
think. Like if if if there's going to be
a rally to a new all-time high, then it
should occur after the death cross and
the death cross should occur around
November 12th or so, right? Like if you
were to zoom in on this chart and just
kind of extend the 50-day moving average
a little bit and then maybe extend the
200 day moving average, it looks like
they might cross maybe maybe a little
bit after November, maybe like November
14th. So it could be like a week from
the recording of this video. Uh maybe a
little bit less, depends on how quickly
the prices change. Um, but that's
essentially what I'm looking at. And if
if the death cross arrives and if
there's not a rally and we get those
weekly closes below the 50we, then yes,
I I think it would be time to, you know,
to just be like, all right, like we we
are going into our 2026 downturn. The
good news is that if we don't have a
euphoria phase before the downturn, then
you could argue the downturn won't be as
bad because you won't have, you know,
all these new retail participants that
FOMOed in at the top providing us sell
pressure all the way down. So, it it
could be a lot more like that 2019 style
drop where it just kind of slowly goes
down uh and it and it might take place,
you know, for the first half of of 2026.
When you say a softer downturn, what
would it look like? Because for the past
few cycles, we Bitcoin was down 94% to
77%ish.
What would this look like in your
prediction?
>> Yeah. So, I guess two an two ways to
answer it. If if the top is in or if
there's only a slightly higher high,
right? So, I mean, even if Bitcoin were
to go to 130K or 140K, it's not going to
bring retail back, right? like that's
clear. Slightly higher Bitcoin prices
aren't going to do anything. Um, you
need altcoins to really move in order to
bring retail back and 140k Bitcoin isn't
really going to durably do that. I would
say if the top is either in or close to
being in, then you're probably looking
at around a 50% pullback. Um,
>> basically a pullback just to the 200E
moving average and and and also sort of
back near the prior all-time highs,
right? So somewhere between 60 to 70K
would be my guess would be kind of the
main target uh for a a pullback into the
year of 2026.
If if the cycle's not over and we have a
much larger rally that like kind of
takes everyone by surprise, then you
would probably have a deeper pullback.
Um maybe like a 70% pullback. And that
would actually be more in line with what
we've seen in in the prior cycles
because you're right, the first bare
market was 94%. The second one was 87,
the third one was 84, the fourth one was
77. And so if you just kind of
extrapolate that, it would make you
believe that the next bare market could
be around 70%, plus or minus 4% or so.
So between say 66% to 74% draw down. But
I think you're only going to get that in
2026 if you really see a more euphoric
ending to the year. If you don't see a
more euphoric ending to the year, then I
might I would probably more so be in the
camp of of of just a 50% pullback.
>> Is it also because um most of the buyers
are institutions and they don't panic
sell or why is this happening?
>> Yeah, I mean it's it's basically the
same thing as as 2019, right? I mean
like if you don't have euphoria then you
don't get massive capitulations. You
just kind of get a slower draw down. I
mean just kind of ignore the pandemic.
you just get sort of a a more controlled
draw down as we just go through we would
likely enter into a period where people
are are remaining optimistic about the
Fed cutting rates and and they're going
to like you know watch for Jerome Powell
to be replaced as a chair at the Federal
Reserve and for someone new to come in
and replace uh or you know start the
money printer back up lower rates and I
think that might keep Bitcoin from you
know from getting that like 80% drop. uh
that would be at least my guess for for
why and of course I mean institutions
will lead to lower volatility but I mean
Bitcoin has been experiencing kind of
like decreased volatility from one cycle
to another um every cycle and of course
this cycle we could we could sort of say
it's because of institutions but it's
also just the natural evolution of of
the asset in my opinion
>> the Fed plans to end uh QT by the end of
year and people are expecting well well
that means uh the market is going to go
crazy, but it's not really happening.
For people that are not following this
very closely, can you explain to the
everyday person what that means? What
does QT ending means?
>> So QT ending would mean the Fed stops
rolling off assets from their balance
sheet and they might start expanding it
again and going into what we call
quantitative easing. um
>> at this point I mean what it what it
typically means is that higher risk
assets stop bleeding against lower risk
assets like automatically right so like
one of the things that's been obvious
this cycle is that altcoins bleed to
Bitcoin you know and that you know and
in stocks you know micro cap companies
like the Russell bleed to the to the S&P
500 or bleed to the magn magnificent 7
while that could still continue and you
know for for a lot of them it's not as
as easy as of a trend to call right so I
mean in in the last cycle when
quantitative tightening ended um it it
actually marked this top by Bitcoin
dominance right here so you can even you
can even line up the end of quantitative
tightening to the to the Bitcoin
dominance chart and see that right when
QT ended that was when Bitcoin dominance
topped and so I would argue that when QT
ends it likely would correspond on to
Bitcoin dominance finding a a top for a
while. That would be my my guess. I
think a lot of people assume that just
because QB returns that you're going to
have like this massive move in the
markets and it doesn't mean that you
won't eventually. But remember last
cycle when QE started, Bitcoin actually
went down first, right? Like it it
actually started off by going down for a
little while and then it went up. So,
I'm just saying that, you know, if they
start QT in December, that's right
before 2026, and 2026 is a midterm year,
and midterm years tend to be bare
markets. So, my guess is that this phase
right here that we saw in 2019 after QE
began will be kind of the narrative for
the 2026 bare market, which again is a
normal thing. Um, bare markets are are
really normal. Like they're they're in
Bitcoin, they happen every four years or
so, right? Like it's not it's not that
abnormal for that to happen. So, that's
kind of what I I think will happen. I
think it'll it'll be a nice narrative.
It might lead to some short-term rallies
by all Bitcoin pairs and and and renewed
interest in the short term, but I think
by 2026, we likely will enter into a
downturn in the market. And my guess is
it'll it'll at least laugh last for the
you know for the first half of the year.
I don't I if there's not a euphoria
phase between now and and the end of the
year then the bare market maybe would
end in the summer rather than going
through the entire year.
>> Um but that's just kind of it's just
speculation at this point, right? I I
don't know how the year's exactly going
to end.
>> Did you just say the bare market would
be about half a year? That's pretty
short.
>> So normally bare markets are a year,
right? Normally bare markets are one
year. Um and and so I I think we have to
be I I think that if if the top's in
then I think the base case has to be
that the bare market low is in October
of 2026. Like that
>> I feel like has to be base case if the
top is in. But I mean, I could see an
example where where Jerome Powell is
replaced in May and they they introduce
a much more dovishfed chair that just is
all about rekindling the animal spirits
and and that might keep Bitcoin from
dropping too much. It wouldn't be like
completely unheard of in the
cryptoverse. Um, if you look at if you
actually look at last cycle, Ethereum
found a low in June of the midterm year,
right? Like so it actually bottomed out
really quickly uh in the summer. So it's
not impossible, you know, for for
Bitcoin to to do something similar um if
if it plays out like that. But again, I
I think base case has to be that it it
takes a year. But I I'm gonna I'm gonna
start looking for, you know, good
opportunities probably in the summer of
2026.
>> What chart would you be looking at?
>> So, I mostly look at at just sort of
like the the risk levels uh is is one
good thing to look at. I mean, you can
look at at a lot of different charts.
One of them though is is uh this chart.
Here we go. So, essentially what it
shows you is is just when when is it a
good time to buy, when is it a good time
to sell? And anytime you go to like
below 0.2 two risk, it tends to be a
really good time to buy. And the last
time we were at 0 2 risk or below it was
November of 2022. So my guess is we'll
see that opportunity again occur in
2026. And when it does, I think that's
usually a pretty good time to sort of,
you know, weight your buys a little
heavier into into the market. So that's
one thing you could use. You know,
there's there's plenty of other things,
but that's probably the main thing I
would use. Do you invest a lot more
during the these periods or h how does
it work? What's your strategy?
>> Yeah, so I use something called like
dynamic DCA. So if you look at a
simulation for buying Bitcoin and you
just DCA, let's say you DCA $100 a week
uh since 2014 and and let's actually
take it out, you know, to the current
day instead of in March. But if you if
you just did that, then you would have
invested about $57,000 if you started in
2014, and it would currently be worth
about $4 million, right? By just doing
$100 a week for the last, you know, 11
years. Um, that's a normal DCA strategy.
If you try to invest the same amount,
but do it dynamically based on like kind
of where the risk metric is. So it kind
of means you just put in more uh when
the risk is low and then you put in less
when it's a little bit higher. So So
again, in this case, we would have
invested around 57K.
So just to kind of like back that out, I
don't know exactly. Um let's let's say,
okay, so that'd be if your X is about
71,
guess 72, that that means you would have
invested around 57,000. But if you
follow the risk levels and kind of
weight it according to the risk, then
you're looking at a portfolio worth 7.5
million as opposed to 4 million by just
doing sort of a regular DCA. So that's
kind of what I use and and and so
basically this is the way it works,
right? You just have you kind of set
your X amount. It's like just a nominal
amount. That's what you're going to do
every week so long as the price is below
a certain risk level. But then the lower
the risk goes, uh, that's where you
start to do a lot more. So for instance,
if one week when the risk is say 0.5,
you put in a $100. If the next week if
the risk is 0.1, you would want to put
in five times the amount, right? So you
put in $500. That way your overall entry
is weighted to lower risk levels rather
than higher risk levels. So a lot of
people what they do is they just put a
lot of money in at the top and then they
get scared to buy at the bottom and so
they have kind of like a higher weighted
risk but you want to make sure you get
your buys in at lower risk levels rather
than higher risk levels. So that's what
I use.
>> This is amazing. And you everybody you
can find that in into the cryptoverse.
What about selling? Do you DCA sell or
you just hold?
>> Yeah, I mean I do. I generally if I if
if the risk gets high enough I will sell
some. Usually I wait until at least it
goes above 6 or 0.7 risk to start to
start scaling out but I would still hold
you know I mean generally historically
speaking I would hold a more a majority
of my position until you get to much
higher risk levels because this cycle
isn't I mean it's playing out more so
like 2019. You could argue it's more of
like a timebased thing than than maybe a
euphoria. So, I I would I I would take
some profits on Bitcoin uh before the
end of the year just because I I am
maybe I'm wrong, but I am mentally
prepared for next year being a bare
market. Um so, I would I would sell some
Bitcoin before the end of the year sort
of in preparation for that. But even in
that case, I would I would still hold I
would say maybe about one-third of my
Bitcoin stack no matter what as just an
acknowledgement that hey, I I can't
possibly know for sure what's going to
happen and I want to make sure I have
some exposure um you know at all times.
>> You know, right now it feels like there
are two opposite forces. one hand people
are talking about this AI bubble
potential crypto bare market and on the
other hand Trump is a businessman and
people are saying that you know the
market is his report card he's not going
to let the market crash and even though
we if we look at you know these tech
companies um the stock prices are crazy
right now but if you look at the profit
it actually goes alongside the stock
prices
unless we're talking about like and you
know, newer or smaller tech companies,
uh, high valuation, no profitability,
like two different forces. How do you
see them, um, play out together?
>> Yeah, I mean, AI is is is really
interesting because
it has I mean, it certainly is making
companies more efficient. I mean, and
and allowing people allowing just
everyday people to start companies they
would have never been able to start in
the past because they don't need a a
massive team of 20 people to get it off
the ground. So, I mean, I I've really
enjoyed AI. As far as whether it's a
bubble or not, I mean, the thing about
bubbles is even if you know, even if you
knew for a fact we were in a bubble, it
doesn't necessarily tell you how do you
make money in the bubble because bubbles
can last for years before they fully
unwind.
>> In fact, if you look at the S&P 500
divided by the money supply, it's
actually played out a lot like the late
1990s. In fact, I you know, we talked a
lot about this, you know, back in March
and April, how this whole pattern is
almost identical to what happened in the
1990s. If you take a bar pattern from
right here all the way up into the peak
and you just simply overlay it on the
current cycle,
>> I mean, even the 20% draw down that we
got earlier this year is almost a
perfect match for the 1998 draw down,
>> right? [clears throat] And so if you
look at that, you could argue that where
we are in in with sort of with respect
to this is we're we're potentially like
right around this part where maybe we
get another sell-off and then sort of
maybe another two 2% drop or something
in stocks. Um and then the government
shutdown ends, we get another rally and
then we kind of come down into the
midterm year stocks. It doesn't mean
that stocks can't continue to stay
elevated even into 2027 potentially. Um,
and that's the hard thing about bubbles
is like even in the.com era. You know,
you could have been fully aware that you
were in a bubble this entire time, but
it didn't mean the market was going to
go down, right? Like the market did
eventually go down, but it took years.
And that's why calling for, you know,
calling tops on that kind of stuff is so
hard because it can be obvious to like
everyone that you're in a bubble and it
and it can seem like the stock market is
so disconnected from the real world.
But, you know, as you said, right, I
mean, Trump, he's a businessman and he
he doesn't want he's not going to let
the stock market go down without a
fight. Um,
and so I think we have to be sort when
it comes to the stock market, it will
always look for a reason to go up,
right? It it needs Sorry. It needs a
reason to go down, not a reason to go
up.
>> Okay. So, stocks
>> explain that.
>> Yeah. So stocks generally go up because
people got 401ks or just p there's all
these passive flows into the market. All
these passive flows. I mean in fact if
you look at the S&P 500 over a very very
long time period, right? If these are
these are 12 month candles, right? So
these are yearly candles. I mean you can
see pretty clearly that the stock market
generally just goes up and to the right,
right? So that is like the natural
progression of the stock market is that
it goes up. Occasionally it goes down,
but in order for it to go down, you have
to have a reason. The two main reasons
that the stock market goes down, a
rising a rising inflation rate, which is
what happened in 2022, right? So, if you
look at the United States inflation
rate, when the when the inflation rate
goes up, that's a reason for stocks to
go down. And you can see that that's
happened in many cycles in the past,
right? Where inflation's going up and
stocks are generally dropping. Okay? So
this has been nothing new. Um it's
happened many many times in the past. It
happened in the 70s. It also happened in
the ' 40s as well. We had we sort of had
like waves of inflation back then too.
And and when you get those waves of
inflation, the stock market is is
usually selling off. Okay. So that's
reason number one. Now inflation hasn't
really been going up a lot recently. It
has gone up, but no one really I mean 3%
inflation the market's going to shrug
off. Now, obviously, a lot of people
don't agree that it's 3%. They would say
that it's higher, but at the end of the
day, like the data suggests that it's
3%. Whether it's right or not, the
market seems to respect it, right? The
market isn't going to care unless it
starts to go back up to like 7% 8%. So,
inflation going up is one bad thing. The
other bad thing is the unemployment rate
starting to go higher. So if you look at
the unemployment rate, what you'll
notice is that when the unemployment
rate starts skyrocketing, skyrocketing,
that's also a time where stocks can go
down. Okay,
>> now the unemployment rate has been going
up, but it's been mostly in a controlled
fashion, right? It hasn't really reached
that nonlinear point where it just goes
straight up and there's no controlling
it. We are absolutely setting ourselves
up for that at some point over the next
couple of years, but it's so hard to
know exactly when it's going to happen.
And one of the ways we know or we can be
pretty sure that it is going to happen
is if you go look at all the macro
indicators for the job market. Like if
you look at like job openings, they're
really low, right? If you look at hires
in the market, they're also really low.
So people aren't really getting hired.
Um it's really hard to find a job, but
people aren't really getting laid off
either in the way that you would expect
in a massive recession. So essentially
layoffs are basically at the pre-
pandemic levels. They're not really that
high. I mean obviously there's a lot of
headlines, but layoffs are also a normal
thing that happen all the time and
they're not they're not as elevated as
they they have been in some of the prior
recessions. Um but whenever layoffs
start and they start to really increase,
the reason why the unemployment rate
goes parabolic at the time is because
not only are people getting laid off,
but also by the way no one's hiring. so
that it becomes harder for people to
find a replacement job. I want to show
you a chart that shows you kind of what
like how the how the market will sniff
out things. Um it'll always look for the
positive. So this is a map of the United
States and it shows you the states
colorcoded orange have a higher
unemployment rate today than they did 6
months ago. Right? So today you can see
that about 23 states have a higher
unemployment rate today than 6 months
ago. But there's pockets of the country
that the unemployment rate has not gone
up over the last six months.
>> And so when you look back at prior
recessions and like when the market
really had a massive downturn,
it was when the entire country had an
unemployment rate going up, right? This
was September 2008. If you look at the
dot bubble burst, right? If you look at
2001, 2002, again, it was the whole
country. So when you look at it, you
know, since 2021, there's definitely
been times where you start to see like
pockets of the country have a rising
unemployment rate, but it hasn't been
the entire country, right? And and what
the market what the market will do is it
will always look for a reason to stay
optimistic, right? If it can find
pockets of optimism, the market will
still try to go higher. the market will
go lower when there's literally no
reason to be optimistic, right? Like
everywhere is struggling and and that's
kind of when you get these these massive
recessions where there's not like you
can't look at this sector over here. A
lot of people have described like you
know this as a rolling recession where
you've had like a a recession in tech
for a little bit and then you had a
recession in manufacturing and then
you've had like a recession in other
areas too. uh but there's it hasn't
really hit the economy all at once and
so you know because a lot of these
industries are regional there's always
been some pocket of of optimism. Um, so
again, the market has to have a reason
to go down, not a reason to go up. And
the two main reasons that it goes down
are inflation and unemployment. And
right now, we're not even getting any of
that data, you know. So, [laughter]
you know, it makes it kind of hard. Uh,
but I mean that that could also be one
of the reasons why why crypto is is is
struggling is because maybe it wants
confirmation that that macro is still
okay. Because again, like with stocks,
there's earnings and and like there's
profitability, right? Like there's
there's like an earnings report. Like an
investor can take a look at the earnings
report, see the company's growing, and
then be like, "Yeah, I want to keep
putting my money into that." With
crypto, we don't really have that,
right? Like it's just speculation. Um
it's just kind of liquidity flows from
one project to another, but it's not
necessarily based on profitability. And
a lot of times what what a lot of
protocols will sort of tout as revenue
or profitability is more so just a
circular economy. Um where where the
where the project will just mint more
tokens and then reward users of the
project with those tokens. So the you
the users who use the project, who use
that blockchain, feel like they're
making money, but really they're just
printing more tokens and so they're
diluting everyone's the value of the the
tokens in circulation, right? So again,
that's not really the same thing as as
as sort of like a durable or sustainable
revenue model. And so when you have
periods like the one we're in right now,
this macro uncertainty, I mean, it's
it's obviously taking its toll on on the
crypto market.
>> For our non-American viewers, we're
talking about the uh government
shutdown. So basically, the Congress
couldn't agree on how to fund the
government, but how does that affect the
market? I think for, you know, a lot of
foreigners, they don't really understand
how it works. So, I mean, yes, the
market doesn't like uncertainty, but how
does that affect the market in general?
>> Yeah. I mean, first of all, your viewers
have every right to be confused about
that because like I absolutely think
it's absurd that this is even a thing in
the United States. Um, and I've sort of
joked before like when we talk about
government shutdowns, we don't even have
to like we don't even have to talk about
um like what country we're talking
about. like everyone knows it's the
United States. Like it it it is kind of
ridiculous. But if you think about it,
like one of the reasons why it could
affect things is a lot of people are
getting are a lot of federal workers are
furoughed, right? So they're not at work
and whenever the government shutdown
ends, they can get a lot of back pay. Um
there are a lot of workers that are
currently working because their job is
like essential. They need they have to
work. We can't just not use the you we
need the labor, but they're not getting
paid. Um, so if people aren't getting
paid, that's directly taking liquidity,
right? Like it's directly taking money
away from people that would have
otherwise had it. And then they're just
not able to to invest and things. So
they're they're more worried about can
they pay their mortgage this month? Can
they buy groceries this month? And if if
we don't know if the government shutdown
keeps getting postponed and postponed,
it just it it r it raises the
uncertainty, you know, more and more and
more um because people start I mean,
think about it. It's now been what 5
weeks. And so people have missed
multiple paychecks at this point. And so
the longer that goes on for, the more
difficult it becomes. Now, as as the
longer the government shutdown goes on
for the constituents of of people on
both side of the aisle, right, whether
you're a Democrat or Republican,
historically, both parties get blamed
for the government shutdown. It's not
one or the other. Both sides get, you
know, start taking the blame and and
usually a lot of times the pressure will
come once stocks start to drop. So, you
know, over the last week or so, we saw
stocks start to drop. if they continue
to drop, then the pressure will start
mounting on on politicians to come up
with a with a solution so we can get
things moving back to normal. Um, and in
one case, very clear and it's even
affected affected my family is air
travel, right? A lot of airport a lot of
airports in the United States, we we've
seen 10% I think of cancellations. Um,
there's just not a lot of air there's
not enough people in in air traffic
control. My wife was actually stuck on
the tarmac uh on an airplane for over an
hour. And the reason why was because
they did not have enough air traffic
controllers. So, it's going to it's
leading to it's going to lead to reduced
travel, right? Which is going to slow
things down. It's going to take a hit on
GDP. Um this is all going to have
negative effects and it just takes a
while for it to filter through. And now
that we're kind of in week five, it is
starting to, you know, to affect various
industries. And the longer it goes on
for, the more industries it will start
to affect. And then, of course, with
less liquidity, when people don't have
their paychecks, that leads to, you
know, just overall less investment into
into the market.
>> How long could this last?
>> Well, I think the prediction markets are
suggesting it'll end in about mid
November, but I I have no idea. I mean,
this is already the longest one we've
ever had. I think the second longest one
was in like 2018. If you told me that it
lasts until December, like, I wouldn't
necessarily be that surprised, but I
think if it lasts until then, we're
going to have a lot of issues going on.
So, I I'm I'm I'm willing to be
optimistic and and hopefully they can
end it, you know, end it within the next
week or two.
>> I think I've watched your video and you
said narrative follows the price, right?
So, when the stock market drop,
everyone's looking for a reason. Why is
the market dropping? Oh, it's the
government shutdown. Do you think um the
statement is true? Narrative follows
price and what usually moves the price
first? Like is it psychology, liquidity?
What what is it?
>> Yeah, I mean I think there's a lot of
like just flows like flows in the
market. Um there's like windows of
weakness and and windows of strength
where liquidity tends to to be better
than other times. Um, like a lot of
times in in Q3 liquidity uh tends to be
lower like there's just not as much
moving around and it could be due to you
know all sorts of things but um you know
taxes can be a big big example like when
people are paying taxes and whatnot that
can obviously have have an effect on the
markets
>> um or or flows.
>> I think that a lot of I mean there
there's seasonality I would argue
seasonality is only like 60 to 70%.
There's obviously like liquidity
conditions. I mean, you know, in 2020
when the Fed printed $6 trillion,
obviously that had an effect on markets.
I think the news headlines aren't nearly
as important, right? And and so like
this year, we've seen a lot of news
headlines for crypto that that sound
really bullish, right? They're like,
"All right, it sounds really good, but
Bitcoin's still trading at the same
price it was a year ago." So that's kind
of proof right there that maybe the
narratives don't really mean as much and
that it has more so to do with things
like monetary policy and and liquidity.
And I I think that plays a much bigger
role, right? Like when you have interest
rates higher and higher and higher and
you're you know the balance sheet of the
Fed is going lower and lower and lower,
that's going to reduce overall risk
appetites in higher risk assets like
altcoins. But when you go to lower
interest rates and money printing that
increases the risk appetite. So I think
I think I think a lot of it is is kind
of related to that. I think too like by
the time you see the move in the market
you know it's it's or by the time you
see the headline you you can't really
profit from it because there's way
there's other people that have things
coded up and and whatnot that that
reacts in a much faster time frame than
any any of us could ever hope to react
in. So yeah, I just don't think it it's
a great it's a great way to navigate the
markets because you can come up with a
narrative to you know to to to sort of
explain anything because I mean like you
know kind of coming into Q4 a lot of
people were bullish right and they had a
lot of narratives to support that
bullish view and now that we're not
pumping then people are trying to find a
reason for it and now the reason is oh
it's because of the government shutdown
but in 2013 we had a government shutdown
that literally started the exact exact
same day of the year that this one did.
The exact same day. And then Bitcoin
went up during that government shutdown.
Right. So, um there's not necessarily a
rhyme or reason to that stuff. I mean, I
think a lot of it just has to do with
monetary policy and and overall
liquidity.
>> If it's about liquidity and uh monetary
policy, then why is the stock market up?
>> Yeah, that's a good question. It's so so
crypto is further up the risk curve. So
it it responds quicker to to sort of
lower liquidity and and that kind of
stuff than the stock market does. The
stock market, if you think about it,
>> has a lot more passive flows. Like
there's so many millions of Americans
that are just passively buying the 401k.
So because they're buying or not buying
the 401k, they're buying the S&P in
their 401k. And so because they're
buying like these index funds, they're
buying Nvidia whether they know it or
not, right? They're they're buying Meta
and Microsoft and Google like they're
buying all that stuff whether they know
they are or not and that's lead and
that's why the stock market is not
really a great indicator for the economy
is because like there's all these like
passive flows that happen uh that that
can be somewhat you know disconnected
from what's really going on um in the
economy. So, I think that's one of the
reasons why why crypto gets hit first.
Like if if as macro conditions start to
deteriorate, the the riskier stuff
starts taking a hit first because that's
where people are going to cut their
spending first, right? Like if you let's
imagine you're just like the an everyday
American, you have a job, you have a
401k, and then you also invest a little
bit in crypto, right? And then let's
say, you know, you you start to come
into hard times. Maybe you're furoughed
because of the government shutdown. What
are you going to do first to find
liquidity to pay your bills? Are you
going to go take money out of your 401k
and take a tax hit? That's, you know,
probably not, right? You're you're
you're going to go to the stuff that's
easier to sell that that aren't going to
have those same issues. And the easier
stuff would be something like like
crypto.
>> That makes sense. Um, I watched Anthony
Pompiano, I think earlier this year, and
he was talking about that the government
simply will not allow a recession. Um,
the money printer won't stop. And even
if we see a huge correction and we call
it bare market, as long as you're
holding good asset,
the the price will eventually come up.
Do you think this um this idea is is uh
healthy
>> over a long enough period of time?
risk assets do go up, right? I mean, if
you look at the S&P over the last
hundred years, you can see that. That
doesn't mean you can't go through five
to 10 year periods where that's not
true. You know, there's plenty of of
loss decades where the price the stock
market just goes sideways um or goes up
and down and up and down. That happens a
lot. I mean, do I think they're going to
keep printing? Yes, I think they will.
Um, I think at some point we're going to
reach kind of a a time where
they're going to want to print and
they're going to want to lower rates a
lot, but you might have inflation
starting to pick back up. And so that
could lead to sort of a checkmate moment
for the Federal Reserve because they
have a dual mandate for maximum
employment and stable prices. And so
when you have only one issue, it's easy.
You know, you only have like if you have
rising unemployment, then you have a
clear thing to do. You just lower rates.
If you have a rising inflation rate,
then you raise rates, right? It's not
clear what do you do when you have a
rising inflation rate and a rising
unemployment rate. And that like that
could lead to a dynamic where the
markets, you know, they reach a point
where where we have to go through a
recession, right? Like that is a
possibility. I do think we will have I
mean we've had recessions in the past.
We're going to have another one in the
future, right? Like it's not like we're
never going to have a recession. Like we
will have a recession at some point. Um
and and you know, one of the things that
could happen is as risk assets go up
potentially over the coming years and as
the as the economy becomes harder and
harder for sort of lower income
Americans, that could start to lead to
social unrest where, you know, workers
feel like they can't afford anything and
the people in assets
um just keep getting richer and richer
and so that wealth gap continues to
grow. And if that happens, you might
actually see the long end of the yield
curve go higher if they're not willing
to let a recession happen. Um because if
if if the economy starts to expand again
and accelerate, that's the only way that
that's the only way the long end can go
up. And so I think it could be
eventually they realize that a recession
is actually what we need um to get rates
down. But we're not at that point. Like
we're not at that point yet. And it took
in the 1990s it took many many years for
the Federal Reserve to kind of come to
terms with what what was required. Um
and if you again if you overlay that
with the current business cycle, you
know, that could still be two years
away, right? right? Like it it might not
be until potentially like 2027 or even
2028 before the Federal Reserve reaches
that point. So I I could see a scenario
where Jerome Powell is replaced as chair
in 2026 and they put someone in that
lowers rates a lot, but then that leads
to just inflation coming back. Um and
then the people that that Trump put in
to lower rates might have to do the
unthinkable and raise rates again. and
and and and that is what happened in
1999 and 2000 that finally popped the
bubble is when the Fed ended up having
to raise rates again after they had
lowered them. And so again, like it's a
multi-year process, right? Like I mean
this whole thing could take two or three
more years. Um in fact, it probably
will, right? I think it probably will
cuz you know they're going to stop QT,
they're going to start QE, they're going
to lower interest rates, they're going
to do everything they can to to extend
things. But eventually there will be a a
an economic downturn. Um it's just a
matter it's just a matter of when. And
by the way, one of the reasons for it uh
could be due to AI. You know, like the
very bubble that's keeping prices
elevated. You know, companies are are
are starting to lay people off, right?
they're not hiring because a lot of
these entry-level jobs are being
replaced by by AI. Um, and so while
companies continue to lay people off,
it's leading to to surges in their stock
price, right? Their prices are going
their stock price is going up because
their labor costs are going down.
They're saving money. But where
recessions happen is when you get a
negative feedback loop. When too many
people get laid off, then demand in the
overall economy starts to drop. So that
the demand for the products that those
companies use or create, it drops
because there's so many people out of
work. And when the demand drops for
those products for those companies, it
then makes those companies lay more
people off that then again reduce the
demand for their products. So it leads
to a negative feedback loop. So you
could argue that the the very reason for
the higher valuations right now will
likely be the eventual undoing at the
end of the business cycle. But again
like that that that could still be two
to three years away for all we know.
>> You're talking about the business cycle
and that reminded me of Ralph Pal. He
said the four-year cycle is dead and he
talks about this potential 5year cycle.
Basically the rates stayed higher for
longer QT dragged on and the business
cycle hasn't turned yet. And what he's
saying is that the real top could be
2026.
Um do you lean more towards that or the
four-year cycle? I think for Bitcoin, I
lean towards the four-year cycle. Um,
>> right.
>> But you could have a scenario where you
could where his view could be viewed as
true even if we have a bare market in
the first half of next year. Cuz you
could have a bare market and it be like
every other time and then if next cycle
ends up being a left translated cycle
where you have a top earlier in the
cycle than normal, it might be viewed as
a continuation of the current cycle. But
you could also probably look at it and
objectively say, well, no, we had a bull
market and it topped in Q4, then we had
a bare market in the midterm year, and
then we had another cycle after that.
So, I would view it as a separate cycle,
but I imagine some people uh might view
it as the same. I talked to Arthur Hayes
um in October and he said we are or at
the time we were in an altcoin season
and he said the reason why most altcoins
that we're holding are not pumping is
because they're piece of tokens.
They don't reward holders. Uh but tokens
like Hyperlid and stuff, they actually
went up a lot. So that was his um
altcoin season. What he was saying is
this is what we will get this cycle.
>> We have not had an alt season this
cycle. I don't care what anyone says.
Like all alt season is when altcoins are
durably rallying against Bitcoin. And
you can see it pretty clearly in 2017
and in 2021, right? This cycle we have
not had an all season. It we just
haven't. And in if he said that in
October, you know, by the way, altcoins
put in a new low in October on their
Bitcoin pairs. There has not been an alt
season this cycle. That doesn't mean
there can't be one, but th this is not
what an alt season looks like. Like this
is the the devaluation of altcoins
against Bitcoin. And we might have an
alt season at the end of the cycle, but
we have not been in one. And and I I
think the idea that a single token or a
few tokens pumping is the definition of
an alt season is just simply untrue,
right? Like it it's been Bitcoin season
for the last several years, right? If
you look at Bitcoin dominance,
>> Bitcoin dominance has just been a
massive uptrend for years, right? For
years. And and so the all season that
people are talking about is is sort of
this where dominance like falls off a
cliff. And we haven't we haven't really
had that. Like we've had periods where
it drops a little but nothing, you know,
nothing like what people were were
thinking it was going to be. Like
nothing like what we've seen in the past
where you have these massive drops uh
that that take place over over many many
months. So no, I I don't I don't agree
that that we've had an alt season. I I
think it's mostly just been a Bitcoin
maxi season. You've had a few tokens
outperformed, but when you think about
it, every token that has outperformed
has only outperformed for like one of
the years, right? And and I think the
last time I was on your channel, I think
I was I was talking a little bit about
like Salana. Um and then shortly after I
I think I said in the in the video that
we did that Salana was likely going to
start bleeding to Bitcoin. And I mean
you can see that I mean it did, right?
Like it it has been dropping.
>> So a lot of the tokens that that go
through these rallies against Bitcoin,
they only last for like a few months and
then they just end up decaying, right?
So like Salana did it in 2023. Um, and
you could argue like there's other
tokens that have done it at other times,
right? We saw XRP go up in late 2024. We
saw BNB go up at at um in in sort of
late 2023 a lot into early 2024. But
when you look at their Bitcoin
valuations, right, even if you look at
BNB Bitcoin, it still is nowhere near
the high from like the last cycle,
right? Like they're still really far
down. And so what the the rallies that
we're getting by altcoins keep making
people think that it's an alt season
because that's what they remember.
That's what they want it to be. But in
reality, the altcoin market has been
putting in lower highs against Bitcoin
since 2021, right? Like since September
of 2021, every rally we've had has just
been like essentially a lower high,
right? So I I can't agree with the
statement that that it's an alt season.
I think that you've had selective
altcoins outperform for a few months and
then they start to decay against
Bitcoin. An all season is where every
altcoin or at least most altcoins in the
top 100 are all going up simultaneously
and that's just simply not been the
case.
>> Could it be possible that we don't get
one this time?
>> It is possible. I mean, if you look at
last cycle when quantitative tightening
ended in September of 2019, October or
August, September 2019, when alts
finally bottomed against Bitcoin, it did
not immediately lead to an alt season,
right? Like altcoins went up against
Bitcoin, but it did not lead to like
that phase, the the big phase right
away. And so, I think like we have to be
aware that it could play out like that,
right? Like you could have an example
where you know alt Bitcoin pairs kind of
come down and they get a rally but it
still not be an alt season and we might
just kind of hang out down here for a
little bit and then maybe they start to
go up again next cycle. I think the only
way you're really going to get a a
durable alt season that takes altcoins
back up to like parody with Bitcoin in
terms of their market cap. The only way
you're going to get it in my opinion is
if Bitcoin has a parabolic rally from
here. So, if Bitcoin were to find a low
um and and start to rally and really go
up a lot and then QTN's and maybe Jerome
Powell cuts rates in December, it's
possible to have an alt season, but I
don't think you're going to get a
durable alt season if if Bitcoin doesn't
really start to to move back up, right?
Bitcoin leads the bull market. And if
the bull market's not over, Bitcoin
needs to prove that. And if Bitcoin
proves it, then altcoins might have a
chance. But when you look at that 2019
move uh in the market during
quantitative tightening, you know, when
when when Bitcoin topped in 2019, there
was not an alt season after it, right?
Like altcoins just kind of bled out uh
until until much lower rates happened.
So it is possible not to have an alt
season. But what I would say is if
people more so concentrate in Bitcoin,
then
you can you can decide whether it makes
sense to take a larger position in
altcoins if and when Bitcoin has a big
rally. Because if if you want to treat
this like 2019, in 2019, Bitcoin was
doing the same thing as it is today. It
was taking liquidity from altcoins back
then. It was taking liquidity in order
to stay above $10,000. Now it's doing it
to stay above $100,000, right? So we've
just increased the price 10x. Um, so I
just in order to get an alt season, you
need Bitcoin to really lead the way and
we just haven't we haven't seen that
yet.
>> A couple months ago when Tom Lee was out
with Ethereum Treasury Company, I think
a lot of people were really excited and
they sold their Bitcoin for Ethereum.
Can we look at Ethereum real quick?
Yeah, I mean the first thing I'll say if
you sold it, I mean the ETH Bitcoin
chart, this this drop was always a very
likely outcome for Ethereum to get this
drop. Um, primarily because when when it
topped here, it corresponded with
Ethereum's USD valuation sweeping the
prior all-time high. And I didn't think
that Ethereum's first rally to an
all-time high would be sustained. I
thought it would get rejected. And so
that was the reason why to become
bearish on ETH Bitcoin there. I think
that I think that ETH is likely not
going to start moving up again against
Bitcoin until probably December. Um,
that doesn't mean it can't bounce around
these levels, but my guess is it's going
to take until December for ETH to start
going back up against Bitcoin. I do
think it looks like it's constructive
here, right? Like you have a low and
then you have a higher low and then
another higher low potentially. Um, but
I do think that in the short term, it
will continue to take a backseat to
Bitcoin into early December. If you look
at at 2017, Ethereum dropped against
Bitcoin into early December right here.
That's also when QT is going to end in
early December. Also in 2020, you know,
Ethereum dropped against Bitcoin into uh
December as well. And there's a lot of
examples where Ethereum kind of fades to
Bitcoin into December, right? Even in
2016, Ethereum sort of dropped against
Bitcoin into December. In 2018, Ethereum
dropped against Bitcoin into December.
Um, and so on and so forth, right? Even
in 2019. So, you can kind of see like
from a seasonality point of view, it's
better to kind of fade Ethereum's
Bitcoin valuation in August, right? Like
fade it in in the summer and then and
then get back into it once you get into
into December. Um you you've mentioned
before that alt season never happened
until uh alt and bitcoin pair hit 0.25.
Where are we now?
>> Yeah, I mean it's interesting because I
mean by some measures you could argue we
already hit 0.25. Right now we're at 38
but just a few weeks ago we went all the
way down to 0.29. If you include USDC
into this metric, which you should
probably you could see that it actually
already went to 0.25. So there is some
validity to the idea that like all right
maybe it will find a low but I think
that in the short term it still makes
sense to to be sort of bullish on
Bitcoin dominance into early December um
would be my sort of my base case. If you
look at total 2 minus USDT divided by
Bitcoin you can see that the valuation
we're at today is the same exact
valuation that all Bitcoin pairs were at
in in November of 2017. Right? And there
was a rally by all Bitcoin pairs, but
then they still went to a lower low by
the beginning of December. So, you know,
I think for all Bitcoin pairs, this
includes Ethereum cuz So, so this one
won't go to 0.25. This is because this
one includes Ethereum. I could see this
one dropping back down to that low right
there in June and then finding like a
double bottom on it, which would then
correspond total 3 minus USDT divided by
Bitcoin likely going to a slightly lower
low once again. Um, and then probably
rallying off that. That's kind of how I
think it's going to play out.
>> Um, if you could look at one chart, like
a retail investor that doesn't follow
the market every day, but if they can
look at one chart religiously every
single day, just to time their exit, uh,
what would that chart be?
>> One chart that I like to look at is just
this sort of this regression chart. This
is the total cryptocurrency market cap.
Um, and it just kind of shows you like
kind of like a more broader view of
where we are in the cycle and whether
we're undervalued or overvalued and it
kind of helps you keep tabs as to like
sort of the macro sort of the macro
moves in the market. So maybe this would
be a good one to look at.
>> We are in early November right now. At
what Bitcoin price would you personally
start questioning if the bare market is
ending? We're talking we we talked about
the 50 um week moving average. What is
the price range? You mean the bull
market is ending?
>> Yeah,
>> I would say if we get a couple of weekly
closes below 100K, like we're probably
done.
>> Yeah, I would say. I mean, the 50 weeks
at 103, but I think that 100K level is
is very meaningful. Um, and like in 2019
when Bitcoin gave up 10K, you know, it
it really started to go down. So, I I
think really 100K is kind of the line in
the sand that, you know, as long as
we're above it, sentiment's generally
okay. But when you go below it,
sentiment quickly starts to deteriorate.
>> Back to the altcoin season topic, the
chart that you used earlier represents
the whole altcoin market and there are
so many more altcoins now. Could it be
that even if the chart shows that we are
already at around 0.25 that individual
coins people hold won't move much just
because everything is so diluted right
now? Yeah, I mean it's it's possible.
Though I do think that as as the asset
class matures, I'm I'm hopeful that
investors will will think more clearly
about where they should be putting their
money rather than just throwing it into
like memecoin pump and dump scams
because I feel like that malinvestment
of capital has actually been very
negative for the crypto industry. I feel
like a lot of developers probably just
went over to AI because like what's the
point of developing in crypto when
someone who creates a memecoin is going
to outperform, you know, your your
tokens life lifetime return just because
of because they paid some influencer to
shill it, you know. Um
>> yeah. So yeah, I mean I think there is
some some level of like there's been so
many altcoins and there's only a certain
amount of money that goes into the
altcoin market and so as you liquidity
has just been getting spread thinner and
thinner across the altcoin market and so
it leads to, you know, relatively
lackluster gains in a lot of the
altcoins.
>> Well, a lot of people probably still
hold their altcoin bags right now. What
would be your suggestions for people?
This could be a very good ending for
this video, I think, because a lot of
people have been very depressed.
>> What I would say is is is, you know,
learn your lesson, right? Don't get too
upset. We've all gone through it. Like,
I went through the whole altcoin stuff
in a prior cycle and I have to be a lot
careful, a lot more careful with
altcoins today. Just treat it as tuition
and and don't lose faith in investing in
general because you had a few bad um
investments in the altcoin market. It's
never too late to start doing the right
thing. Um, that's kind of my my view. If
you bought a lot of altcoins, you saw
them go up, and then maybe you've roundt
tripped your bags. Uh, maybe in 2026,
focus more on on accumulating projects
that, you know, you actually do believe
in long term, right? And I think that is
is kind of a good place to start. And
also I would I would tell people to like
to value their portfolio in Satoshi's
rather than US dollars because if you
start doing that like it'll help you
figure out if putting your money in an
altcoin really makes sense. Like I've
seen so many people throw all their
money away into an altcoin that just
keeps on bleeding to Bitcoin, you know,
and they think it's going to change and
then it just never changes and it goes
on for eight years and they still think
they I mean like even Litecoin, you
know, I have the the uh the the the
intern that runs the Litecoin Twitter
account, you know, constantly calling me
out and I mean I kind of like going back
and forth with them if I'm being honest.
Um but you know, if you look at the
Litecoin chart against Bitcoin, I mean
it just bleeds over a long period of
time, right? Like it's not
>> it's not like it's not like I'm saying
that's what I want to happen. Uh but
it's just what happens to a lot of these
projects. They they have their cycle in
the sun and then they just bleed out to
Bitcoin for the rest of their for for
the rest of their life their lifespan.
Altcoins are not a long-term investment.
They're a short-term investment. Bitcoin
is a long-term investment.
>> Altcoin as in all altcoins are just
smaller ones.
>> All coins all altcoins are are shorter
term investments. I mean, I own
Ethereum. I bought some Ethereum back in
April, but how can I with a clear
conscience say it's a long-term
investment when it's trading below the
price it was trading at in 2021, you
know?
>> Um, and and we're now four years later
and Ethereum is trading less than the
price it was trading at in November of
2021. Um, so like it and again, we
watched the Ethereum Bitcoin valuation
go from 0.085 to 0.017. 017, right? To
me, that's not a long-term investment.
That's like, you know, you want to try
you want to try to time when it bottoms
against Bitcoin and maybe ride that
wave, but it's not necessarily a great
long-term investment.
>> A lot of Chinese speaking audience buy
Cardano. What is your view on that?
>> Yeah, so one of the things I said a long
time ago, Cardano was going to go to uh
400 Satoshi's and everyone said why it
wouldn't happen. And what's funny is is
my prediction was too optimistic because
at least on Binance it went to 261
Satoshi's. Um so when you when I look at
a chart like this it like I mean it's
just been bleeding for a long time. When
it comes to ADA the main chart I look at
isn't even the Bitcoin valuation. It's
the Ethereum valuation because when you
buy an altcoin you you want it to go up
against Bitcoin. If it's not going up
against Bitcoin, then you really have to
question like like like what's the
point, right? If you are going to buy
it, then before you buy it, look to see
what it's doing against Ethereum because
I think you could argue that Ethereum is
essentially could be, you know, could
act as the index for the altcoin market.
And the problem is that ADA just
continues to bleed against Ethereum as
well. So, you know, and I used to be
very bullish on ADA. I mean, you know,
some of the very first videos on my
channel, I was talking about ADA when it
was less than $2 back in 2019, and I was
very bullish on it. And I mean, it
ultimately went to $3. But I also look
at a chart like this, and I just see
lower highs and lower lows, and I have
to ask myself like, is that a long-term
investment? And to me, like if I see if
I see it bleeding to Ethereum and I see
it bleeding to Bitcoin, you know, do I
really want to sit in it for 4 years
just so maybe once every four years it
has a nice little rally? Probably not.
So, you know, it's a tough call. I I
will say that if it's going to get a
rally against Bitcoin, it'll happen
within the next two months. If it
doesn't happen in the next two months,
then
it's probably not going to happen. Like
there's plenty of charts that look like
this where people think they're going to
to find support at the range lows and
then they just don't. They they end up
putting in a lower high and a lower low
because you could look you could look at
this chart and see that technically
that's a lower high and a lower low. So
you might end up starting to see lower
lows as well. Um so that's kind of what
I would look at. And and just to give
you an idea of like what I'm talking
about, if you look at some of these
relic altcoins from prior cycles, like
Dash, that one's been popular recently
because it's been going up, right? Like
it's been kind of making its way through
the news. But even in this case,
>> like you can see there there used to be
kind of a range low for it as well that
it would hold as support and then
eventually it it just kind of fell off
and and then bled a ton. Um, and of
course now it's getting a nice rally and
usually, you know, once every four or
five years, like it'll it'll get a nice
rally, but it it doesn't mean that it's
not eventually just going to continue
bleeding. Um, so that's kind of what I
look at. But again, yeah, I mean, some
of these older altcoins have certainly
started to to to rally recently, but I
mean, even in this case with a with a
token like Dash, you know, it's still
down 99% against Bitcoin, right? like
these rallies that look really great.
Again, they're it's still down 99%. And
that's kind of the that's kind of the
reality that that most altcoins
eventually face is that like if you hold
it long enough, you might find a several
hundred% rally, but you still would have
been better off holding just Bitcoin.
>> I love that you make it very simple and
even a person that is not as technical,
it is very easy to understand. And if
you want to check out the charts that
Ben uses today and all the charts that
he uses to time the market, you can
check out the description box below.
There is a huge sale going on.
Definitely check it out because it could
really help your trading and investing
strategy and your journey. Well, Ben,
thank you so much for being on the show
today. Um, you have a huge fan base in
Asia. Please come back soon.
>> Thanks for having me. Pleasure to be
here and yeah look forward to coming